KARTIK SHAH

kartik.isworking@gmail.com | +61 404 874 569

https://ikartiks.github.io/ | https://github.com/ikartiks | https://in.linkedin.com/in/ikartiks

Summary of Experience

I have 6.3 years of experience in various domains like Banking, digital marketing & healthcare. My core forte is Android, but I have worked on both frontend and backend using technologies like Angular JS, Spring & Hibernate. I have also worked on NoSql technologies like CouchDb which offers in built sync mechanism with conflict resolution. I provide end to end Omni channel experience to clients as per requirements. I like building products. Love to teach & learn. This is a std. single page resume, detailed available on website. Looking for an opportunity at Sydney, New South Wales, Australia (State sponsored PR holder).

Education

Bachelor of Engineering, Information Technology, Mumbai University, 2011

Certifications

Google & Udacity's Android Developer Nanodegree, Udacity's Self Driving Car Nanodegree (Ongoing)

Technical Skills

Strong: Android, Kotlin, BackBase, CouchDB, Building voice actions with Home

Knowledgeable: Angular JS, Spring, JPA, Hibernate, HTML, CSS, SQL, Oracle, Python, Machine Learning, core PHP, RXJava /RXKotlin,

observables

Methodology: Agile using Jira & Pivotal Tracker, SCRUM, Kanban boards.

Tools: Jenkins for Continues integration, Burp Suite for network security, J-meter for load testing, GIT for version control.

Work Experience -

Apr 2019 - Present, Frollo Sydney, Australia

- I work on an app for Volt bank, build on top of the Frollo SDK, so my major chunk of work here includes having an aesthetic UI.
- The app allows you to link your bank account, view your transactions, expenses set savings goals.
- I mainly work on the frontend of this application, although I have worked parts of the frollo SDK and app as well.

Jan 2019 – April 2019, Telstra via Luvo (contract). Sydney, Australia

Working on Telstra's 24x7 app. I worked mainly on their messaging module, as well as redesigning the app modules.

Indian Experience - 6 years

OCT 2015 – OCT 2018, Tata Consultancy Services. IT Analyst, Mumbai

- Leading a team of 7 developers to build a Banking application (HDFC). App has 10M+ installs & 3.9 * rating.
- Built a hybrid app using phonegap for Sony Picture Entertainment's Digital windows project.
- Built, developed websites (backend and frontend) for Sony Picture Entertainment's SmartR project, SOAR

For complete Indian experience view detailed resume.

Major Projects

Frollo	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=us.frollo.frollo.prod	Kotlin, LiveData, TDD
Telstra 24x7	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.telstra.mobile.android.mytelstra	Kotlin, RxJava / RxKotlin, TDD
HDFC Bank	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.snapwork.hdfc	Android, Backbase, Kotlin
Vocabulary Flashcards	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.kartik.grevocab	Android, Kotlin (my product)
YRD Health app	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.yrdtechnologies	Android, Kotlin (in beta request access)
EPMWare	http://epmware.com/	Spring, Hibernate, JPA, AngularJS
Dr. Fixit	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pidilite.drfixit	Hybrid app development
Team Tracker	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.graymatrix.teamtracker	Android, Couch database
USL's RCB IPL Team	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.royalchallengers.android	Android, core JS, PHP
USL's Signature	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.usl.signatureselfies	Android, core JS, PHP
Selfies app		
Britania's iHealthU	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ihealthu.program.challenge	Android, core JS, PHP
Adlabs Imagica	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.adlabs.themepark	Android, core JS, PHP
Castrol Cricket	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.castrolcricket.android	Android, core JS, PHP
EC Diwali cracker app	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.experiencecommerce.android	Android, core JS, PHP
Awards & Loadorship		

Awards & Leadership

- Best team award at TCS, Client appreciation across multiple projects.
- Complete sponsorship to Mobile developer summit held in Bangalore 2013.
- Complete sponsorship to Udacity & Google's Android Developer Nanodegree course.
- Complete sponsorship to Google's Android Career summit Bangalore 2016 for top 50 selected Android developers across India.
- Conducted multiple trainings in JAVA, Android & JavaScript at TCS, single training on Machine Learning.